[Music]
it finally feels like I am nearing the
end of my pregnancy only a few months to
go and I have naturally been pretty
tired and increasingly out of breath so
today I decided to cheer myself up a bit
by putting a little extra time into
getting dressed brushing my hair putting
on some jewelry and showing myself some
care which is easy to forget to
do when I first realized I was going to
have a baby I read a book about
motherhood that described the process as
a radical Act of surrender and
acceptance letting your body and mind
surrender to a completely new
experience I think that whenever we're
facing times of change or trying to
change ourselves in some way it can be
so freeing to take account of what you
can control and surrendering to the rest
in a world where so many of us are
habitual Warriors including myself we
can feel fearful of stepping into the
unknown and really leaning into the
mysteries of
life can be the hardest thing to let go
and yet with practice a quiet peace
begins to brew that slowly takes over
and makes you wonder how you ever
tolerated living any other
way as my body has begun to feel heavy
and I'm certainly not as mobile as I
used to be I've been home a bit more
which has motivated me to take on the
project of simplifying my home and
preparation for a new era using this
chance to move things about and do a bit
of redecorating for
[Music]
spring
Luke and I have been trying to downsize
declutter and simplify mostly budget
wise but I think it also helps to do it
physically as well I find that when I
simplify my space especially as like a
little spring cleaning I feel like it's
also spring cleaning my mind a little
bit I think that if you do a lot of
decluttering with a very mindful
attitude you can become aware of your
own thoughts and your own Tendencies and
things you want to also simplify within
I am expecting to have to take some time
off of work and I don't know how much
time off of work that will be um
thankfully we have been saving and
trying to prepare so we will be ready
for it but it's still really good I
think to be a little more mindful I
decided that if I do a very big big yard
sale at in the spring hopefully in
another month or so um it might be a
little late winter yard sale My Hope Is
that I can put a portion of those
proceeds towards Wildlife relief and our
forests so that is why I'm going to let
go of things I do not need I want to try
to do a yard sale see how that goes I've
never ever done one before so yes it is
time to simplify I've been using the
library a lot and I think there are a
lot of these books here that other
people might be able to
enjoy
[Music]
think
this was an absolutely amazing survival
story I it was such a page Turner I just
was so amazed and horrified the entire
time so this is one of my very favorite
kind of old vintage books it is just
full of all these amazing
illustrations and it has some full color
illustrations as well this book is one
of my prized possessions not because
I've actually read the book because I've
not read it yet but I received it and I
just think it's so beautiful it's just
look at that cover just look at it oh my
gosh just
oh wow this is another book that is a
prize possession it is so old and worn
but my father-in-law who always keeps an
eye out for really cool books cuz he
knows I'm a book person he picked up
this book for me and I think he found it
um just in a a box of old random books
in a family house I can't quite remember
I'll have to ask him but yes he brought
this one over to me and I absolutely
love it and I actually looked it up
online and um I think it's worth quite a
bit of money I think it's one of the
earlier additions of some of tol keen's
work beautiful illustrations in it my
husband and I already live quite simply
and we are trying to do it even more so
we don't really go on trips unless they
are family trips where it's kind of a
group effort we um don't really do too
many things outside of the house
actually and part of the reason is
because we live in the middle of nowhere
but but um we also are trying our best
not to eat out um pretty much at all
however we are both artists we love art
we love beautiful things so I don't
think our house will ever look quite
minimalist because even though we try to
keep things simple you know I just I
love to decorate I Love to Get Crafty
and he as well he loves to create things
he does wire wrapping he as well loves
just kind of handmade items I find it
quite tricky as someone who loves to
create art and crafts um and do projects
at home like that it's hard to do that
and also keep things quite minimal and
I'm saying that because I'm also a huge
book Enthusiast I talk about books here
I as well receive books from Publishers
due to working at a bookstore so it's
definitely something that is kind of
coming my way all the time however I
certainly do need to simplify so we are
going to attempt to do that I hope this
is some inspiration for you if you need
to do a little bit of spring cleaning
I'm sure there's a lot more I could get
rid of but it's so hard to part with
books especially when you you know you
really you they really have a close
place in your
heart
after I decided what books I was going
to give away I went upstairs to go
through some of my wardrobe as well
making room for new baby
[Music]
supplies I was recently gifted these
handmade baby shirts and I'm absolutely
Enchanted I've received some lovely
gifts recently and Luke and I now feel
well prepared for our new addition and
have felt so much love coming our way it
has been a humbling and beautiful
[Music]
experience it felt really nice to decide
what clothes to give to the yard sale
the process of going through my little
stash of personal items also made me
fall back in love with some very special
pieces of jewelry my husband has made
for me over the years as he is an artist
in his own right and extremely
[Music]
talented the hardest part uh with making
all these decisions for the yard sale is
that I um I have to decide on
pricing and um that's really tricky I
feel like I just want to put everything
as a dollar a wool
scarf a dollar a dollar
$2 I don't know this one I think is very
old it's like a vintage jacket
from maybe this should be like
$5
$5 oh boy this is so hard I have this
dress it's in as far as I can tell
perfect
condition I think $2 $2 I'm really bad
at this I'm terrible at this I'm just
terrible I think it will kind of be
whatever people can afford we'll just do
it that way this little bunny don't let
his adorable face fool you he's just
about the grumpiest little bunny I've
ever had um he's just not happy about
anything in life so it's very funny so
yes this is Bernard in case you missed
his name earlier this year yes he's just
kind of a glass half empty sort of bunny
and this this bunny Luna is just about
the most positive rainbow bunny that
I've ever encountered so their um their
contrast to personalities is really
[Music]
funny
with my simplification journey complete
it felt cathartic to put items in boxes
I had made wonderful progress in making
ample room for our baby to come into our
lives and while this has been a quiet
week spent at home I find that when I'm
feeling a bit tired or down chipping
away at little projects I've been
wanting to do for years helps keep my
body moving and Spirit Light knowing
that life is a series of ups and downs
and we can learn from both parts of the
journey if we're open to what they have
to
[Music]
offer